# RIYA CHADDHA

(857) 405-9051 | Boston, MA | chaddha.ri@northeastern.edu | LinkedIn | Github

### **SUMMARY**

A data-savvy college graduate with 2+ years of experience in Data Engineering and a solid grasp of database and business architecture, driven by a fervor for data engineering and statistical analysis, and now poised to harness analytical skills for the purpose of enhancing corporate performance in the role of a Business Intelligence Engineer.

### **EDUCATION**

Master of Science in Information Systems, Northeastern University Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science, University of Pune

Aug 2023 - Present

Aug 2016 - May 2020

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

**Programming Languages:** Database & Data Warehouses: **Tools & Technologies:** 

Python, Java, R, C, C++, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, AngularJS, Node JS, Typescript, React MS SQL, MySQL, Oracle, PL/SQL, MongoDB(NoSQL), Azure Data Studio, Azure Data Factory

Power BI/DAX, Tableau, Git, RStudio, Talend, Alteryx, Snowflake, Apache Spark, Informatica

Frameworks: TensorFlow, NumPy, Pandas, OpenCV, Sci-kit learn, Matplotlib, PyTorch, Jupyter **Relevant Skills:** 

ETL/ELT process, Data Warehousing, Data Manipulation, Statistical Analysis, NLP, LLM

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Data Engineer, Larsen & Toubro Infotech (LTI)

Aug 2021 - Jun 2023

- Created Power BI dashboards by querying, loading, and transforming data from the Warehouse and Data Mart into SSMS
- Contributed to a 30% increase in decision-making efficiency by delivering interactive and insightful Power BI reports
- Key contributor to Project Release-1 launch, ensuring 94% defect-free results in UAT by collaborating within Azure DevOps
- Earned recognition from executives for pivotal contribution to quality assurance efforts by identifying 60% critical defects

## Data Engineer Trainee, Larsen & Toubro Infotech (LTI)

Jan 2021 - Jul 2021

- Conducted comprehensive Reports Testing, ensuring flawless data flow from Data Warehouse and Data Mart into SSMS
- Revitalized testing efficiency by 90% through the automation of regression and iteration testing using the IPAT framework
- Executed functional testing for insurance applications, including policy, claims and billing within Duck Creek environment

### Android Developer Intern, Optinno Mobitech

Dec 2018 - Feb 2019

- Designed and designed an Android calling and messaging app with diverse functionalities using Android Studio
- Employed SQLite for managing and retrieving contact details to and from the database efficiently
- Implemented message segregation through text analysis, categorizing incoming messages into spam and important

# **ACADEMIC PROJECTS**

## Food Inspection BI: Dallas & Chicago Data Analysis

Jan 2024 - Feb 2024

- Designed and implemented dimensional modeling for analyzing food inspection data from Dallas and Chicago cities
- Conducted data profiling to check quality of data including missing values using Alteryx and y-data profiling tools
- Conducted data staging and cleaning in Talend, including addressing missing values and consolidating columns
- Generated Power BI and Talend dashboards to visualize the analysis done on the clean data and verified it using SSMS

## **Housing Price Prediction using Neural Networks**

Jan 2024 - Feb 2024

- Implemented a neural network model for predicting housing prices using strategic feature selection to enhance accuracy
- Utilizing NumPy, Pandas, Seaborn, sklearn for data manipulation and preprocessing to address dataset inconsistencies
- Applied AutoML and SHAP analysis techniques to evaluate the optimal model, providing explanations for model outputs

### **Inventory Management System**

Nov 2023 – Dec 2023

- Engineered an efficient inventory system for frozen food product management across suppliers and end-users
- Developed insightful Power BI reports to visualize critical information related to the top order lists and inventory stock
- Leveraged SQL Server Management Studio (SSMS) for the design and administration of the database infrastructure

### Classification and Detection of Galaxies using Faster RCNN

Nov 2019 - Apr 2020

- Led training of a machine learning model that successfully classifies galaxies based on the Hubble Sequence
- Operationalized Faster Region-based Convolutional Neural Network (R-CNN) algorithm for an 86% accuracy boost
- Utilized TensorFlow, Keras to train neural networks for galaxy classification, and NumPy, Pandas for data manipulation
- Employed OpenCV for image processing tasks, such as object detection, feature extraction and image segmentation